Why are we so worried about our careers?
我们为什么如此担忧自己的事业？
Partly it’s to do with money, but there’s a psychological aspect to our fears as well.
这在一定程度上与钱有关，但我们的这种担忧也有心理方面的因素。
We worry because we suspect—not wrongly—that the world is full of a frightening sort of person ready to judge us ruthlessly and swiftly: a person we can call a snob.
我们之所以担忧，是因为我们怀疑——而且这种怀疑并没有错——世上到处都有一种可怕的人，随时准备无情而迅速地评判我们，这种人我们可以称之为“势利眼”。
A snob is anyone who takes a relatively small part of us and uses it to come to a rigid conclusion about how much of their attention we deserve.
凡是抓住我们身上相对较小的一部分，并据此得出僵化的结论、判定我们值得他们给予多少关注的人，都是势利眼。
In the past, that might be our ancestry and royal connections.
在过去，这一部分可能是我们的家世以及与王室的关系。
Nowadays, the snob cares about one thing only: what we do for a living.
如今，势利眼只在乎一件事：我们靠什么谋生。
This explains why the first question we will be asked in any new social context is “What do you do?” and according to how we answer, snobs will either welcome us with broad smiles, or leave us in the cold.
这就解释了为什么在任何新的社交场合，别人问我们的第一个问题都会是“你是做什么的？”，而势利眼会根据我们的回答，要么笑容满面地欢迎我们，要么冷落我们。
And that is why we are fired up by such a desperate urge to achieve and impress.
这也就是为什么我们心中会燃起如此迫切的冲动，想要有所成就、给人留下深刻印象。
Sometimes our behaviour is mistaken for greed and vanity, but it is more than this.
有时，我们的行为会被误认为是贪婪和虚荣的表现，但其实不止于此。
A lot of our interest in fancy cars, jobs and houses has nothing to do with materialism.
我们对豪车、光鲜的工作和豪宅的兴趣，很大一部分与物质主义毫无关系。
It has to do with a hunger for the respect and esteem that is only available in our societies through the acquisition of material goods.
它与对尊重和敬重的渴望有关，而在我们的社会中，只有通过获取物质财富才能赢得这种尊重和敬重。
It isn’t the goods themselves we seek; it is the love we stand to gain through our possession of them.
我们追求的不是财物本身，而是通过拥有财物有望赢得的爱。
The next time we see someone driving a Ferrari, we shouldn’t condemn them for their greed; we should pity them for the intensity of their need for love from the world.
下次再看到有人开着法拉利，我们不应该谴责他贪婪，而应该同情他，因为他如此强烈地需要得到世人的爱。
At the root of snobbery is a lack of imagination and confidence about how to decide who in the world is valuable.
势利的根源在于，在如何判断世上谁有价值这件事上，缺乏想象力和自信。
The snobs are brutally misguided and slavish in their beliefs about how the superior individuals can be identified.
在怎样才能识别出优秀的人这一问题上，势利眼错得离谱，而且一味盲从。
For snobs, it is the already acclaimed and already successful who are the only ones worthy of respect.
在势利眼看来，只有那些已经备受赞誉、已经取得成功的人，才值得尊重。
There is no room in their timid, regimented minds to imagine that someone might be clever, kind or good—and yet somehow have been overlooked entirely by society, their qualities lying hidden beneath an unfamiliar veil and having as yet discovered no obvious outlet.
他们胆怯而刻板的头脑里容不下这样的想象：某个人可能聪明、友善或品行端正，却不知为何被社会完全忽视了，其优点隐藏在一层陌生的面纱之下，至今尚未找到明显的施展途径。
The true answer to snobbery is not to say that there is no such thing as a better or worse person, but to insist that better or worse exist in constantly unexpected places and carry none of the outward signs of distinction.
应对势利的真正办法，不是说世上根本没有更好或更差的人，而是坚持认为，更好或更差的人总是存在于意想不到的地方，而且身上没有任何彰显其出众的外在标志。
And because we are such poor judges of the worth of others, our ultimate duty remains to be kind, good, curious and imaginative about pretty much everyone who ever crosses our path.
而且，由于我们如此不善于判断他人的价值，我们的根本职责仍然是：对我们遇到的几乎每一个人都友善、厚道，对他们保持好奇，并用想象力去看待他们。